Guide to the Turner family papers, 1799-1891.
Turner family papers, 1799-1891.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Turner family papers, 1799-1891.
689
.8 cubic ft.
Correspondence.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Chiefly letters written by members of the related Turner, Baker, and Wheeler families, describing their activities as they moved southward and westward from Massachusetts and New York.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Chiefly letters written by members of the related Turner, Baker, and Wheeler families, describing their activities as they moved southward and westward from Massachusetts and New York. Includes letters from Otis and Oliver Baker, theology students at Yale University; Baker and Turner family letters from Lockport and Watertown, New York; letters from Susie Turner, student at Mount Holyoke College (Class of 1853) and teacher at Rockford Seminary; letters from Asa Turner, travelling salesman in the South and Midwest; correspondence between Avery Turner, Cornell University Class of 1873, and his friends at Quincy College and Kansas City Medical College, and later letters relating his work as an engineer for the Atchison, Topeka, and Santa Fe Railroad. Among the Wheeler papers are letters between relatives at an academy in New Bradford, Mass, and at Amherst College; letters from Marshall Wheeler relate to his activities as a clerk in Shelbyville, Kentucky, as a farm owner in Carthage, Ill., as the proprietor of a merchandising business at Quincy, Ill., and to his life as a merchant, plantation and slave owner, and stock and hog producer at Sabine and Cold Springs, Texas.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Turner family.; Baker family.; Baker, Oliver.; Baker, Otis.; Turner, Asa.; Turner, Avery.; Turner, Susie.; Wheeler family.; Wheeler, Marshall.; Amherst College.; Atchison, Topeka, and Santa Fe Railway Company.; Cornell University. Class of 1873.; Kansas City Medical College.; Mount Holyoke College. Class of 1853.; Quincy College.; Rockford Seminary.; Yale University.Divinity School.
Subjects:
Railroads.; Migration, Internal--United States.; Women college students--Massachusetts.; Theological seminaries.; Slaveholders--Texas.; Family--Massachusetts.; Family--New York (State); Agriculture--Illinois.; Merchandising--Illinois.; Agriculture--Texas.; Swine--Marketing--Texas.; Railroad engineers.; Traveling sales personnel.
Places:
Shelbyville, (Ky)--Commerce.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- List of Otis M[arshall?] Wheeler letters in the Avery Turner Papers
  - Carthage, Illinois, Feb. 10, 1834 (Box 1-2)
    Employed by store
  - Carthage, Illinois, Mar. 1834 (Box 1-2)
  - Carthage, Illinois, May 31, 1834 (Box 1-2)
  - Carthage, Illinois, June 27, 1834 (Box 1-2)
  - Carthage, Illinois, Jan. 18, 1835 (Box 1-2)
  - Carthage, Illinois, May 1835 (Box 1-2)
  - Carthage, Illinois, Oct. 15, 1839 (Box 1-2)
  - Sabine Town, Texas, Jan. 25, 1844 (Box 1-2)
    Owns slaves
  - New Orleans, July 9, 1844 (Box 1-2)
    Slaves and goods
  - San Augustine, May 24, 1845 (Box 1-2)
    Introduction
  - San Augustine, Mar. 23, 1847 (Box 1-2)
    War and conditions
  - San Augustine, Nov. 28, 1847 (Box 1-2)
    Austin and crops
  - San Augustine, Sept. 6, 1848 (Box 1-2)
    Low cost of cotton
  - Paducah, Kentucky, Sept. 26, 1850 (Box 1-2)
    Trips
  - Cold Spring, Texas, May 24, 1855 (Box 1-2)
    Great drought in Texas
  - Cold Spring, Texas, Sept. 11, 1855 (Box 1-2)
  - Cold Spring, Texas, May 5, 1856 (Box 1-2)
  - Polk County, Texas, May 22, 1857 (Box 1-2)
  - Polk County, Texas, July 29, 1857 (Box 1-2)
  - Cold Spring, Texas, Sept. 29, 1859 (Box 1-2)
  - Cold Spring, Texas, Dec. 16, 1859 (Box 1-2)
  - Cold Spring, Texas, Jan. 4, 1860 (Box 1-2)
    Vaccination smallpox
  - Cold Spring, Texas, Feb. 19, 1860 (Box 1-2)
  - Cold Spring, Texas, Mar. 10, 1860 (Box 1-2)
    Slavery abolition
  - Cold Spring, Texas, July 4, 1860 (Box 1-2)
  - Cold Spring, Texas, Sept. 5, 1860 (Box 1-2)
    Insurrection re: slavery
  - Cold Spring, Texas, Jan. 20, 1861 (Box 1-2)
    Political cloud
  - Cold Spring, Texas, Mar. 11, 1861 (Box 1-2)
  - Cold Spring, Texas, Sept. 1, 1871 (Box 1-2)
    After the war - free slaves